Register to The Armin Loos Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Armin Loos Papers
1918-1979
MSS 20
Yale University Music Library
6
(12 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and miscellaneous items by and about the German-American composer Armin Loos (1904-1971)
Loos, Armin, 1904-1971
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Armin Loos Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Elizabeth Loos in 1975.
Arrangement
Arranged in 16 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Programs and program notes. III. Newspaper clippings. IV. Biographical and analytical notes. V. Published book by Armin Loos. VI. Items relating to the Armin Loos Memorial Fund. VII. Lecture notes by Loos. VIII. School papers. IX. Photographs. X. Diary and travel notes. XI. Poetry and prose. XII. Miscellaneous cards, certificates, etc. XIII. Lists of musical works by Loos. XIV. Musical works by Loos. XV. Musical works copied or arranged by Loos. XVI. Sound Recordings.
Scope and Contents
The Armin Loos Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Loos's musical compositions, including orchestral music, chamber works, keyboard pieces, songs, and choral music. The correspondence includes letters to and from Loos and family members, composers, conductors, and musical organizations. Loos's life and work are further documented by: programs and program notes; newspaper clippings; writings by and about Loos; photographs; and miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
Mathias Jacob Friedrich Armin Loos, known as Armin, was born in Darmstadt, Germany, on February 20, 1904. Loos's father was a prominent bank director in Dresden and wanted his son to pursue a career in finance. Therefore Armin's education included a degree in jurisprudence from the University of Dresden as well as studies at the Universities of Berlin and Geneva. In the fall of 1924 he studied at the École Supériere de Commerce in Neuchâtel, Switzerland, and in the fall of 1926 he attended a 12-week course at Pitman's School (a business school) in London. His musical training included composition lessons with Paul Buttner in Dresden.
In 1928 Loos came to the United States after a tour of Europe. He was to prepare for a career in banking and arrived with recommendations from German bankers in hand. It was in this year that he published a book in Germany entitled The First Mortgage Gold-Bond of the German Mortgage Banks. In spite of these accomplishments Loos decided to remain in New York, marry, and devote his time to composing. Here Loos taught himself the 12-tone system, and in 1938 he won second prize in a W.P.A.-sponsored choral competition in which William Schuman received first prize, David Diamond third, and Elliott Carter fifth. He became a U.S. citizen in 1940.
The Depression made it impossible for Loos to earn a living as a composer, and in 1940 he went to New Britain, Connecticut, to work in his father-in-law's store, Bloomberg's Curtain Shop. He retired in 1962 after his second heart attack and devoted himself to music until his death on March 23, 1971. He composed many works during this period, and revised many older ones. Loos's enthusiasm and talent were far-reaching. He gave music lectures in his home from 1963 to 1970, and wrote program notes for the New Britain Symphony Orchestra.
Unfortunately, Loos heard only a few of his pieces performed. Many of his works have been performed since his death, thanks to the efforts of his widow, Elizabeth Loos. An Armin Loos Memorial Fund was established to promote the performance of his works. Loos's Aquarius '70 was performed by the Berkshire Music Center Orchestra, conducted by Gunther Schuller on August 16, 1979. His Sonata for Violin and Piano (1971) was performed by members of the Composer's Guild for Performance at Columbia University on April 12, 1979.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Piano music; Songs; String quartets -- Scores; Symphonies -- Scores; Barbirolli, John, 1899-1970; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Loos, Armin, 1904-1971; Loos, Elizabeth; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999; Petri, Egon, 1881-1962; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962; Winograd, Arthur, 1920-2010
- Correspondence, 1924-1979; Series I
  General
  The correspondence has been divided into seven subseries, each arranged alphabetically. The first four subseries are further divided into letters written to and from Loos. The first subseries, "Family," has an additional division which contains letters from Armin's brother Hans to family members. The correspondence is in English, French, and German.
  The family correspondence reflects the impact of the depression and World War II upon the Loos family in Dresden and upon Armin, who came to New York in 1928. Armin's father and brother Kurt were both killed in the war.
  Also included in the family correspondence are letters between Armin and his wife, Elizabeth. Mrs. Loos has extracted those parts of Armin's letters relating to his music. The correspondence concerning musical works contains letters relating to competitions, musical organizations, and requests to conductors to read his music. Among these are letters from Aaron Copland, Richard Donovan, Roy Harris, Serge Koussevitzky, Egon Petri, and Leopold Stokowski.
  - Family, I.A
    - To Loos, from Family, I.A.1
      - Freyberg, Anneliese von (Loos) [sister], 1928-1952; no year Feb 12, Mar 27, Sep 2; 12 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Freyberg, Ewald von [brother-in-law], 1931 Feb 14; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Freyberg, Ewald and Anneliese von, 1951; 2 autograph letters signed, 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
        [in part, autograph]
      - Freyberg, Ewald and Anneliese von, 1930 Jul 13; no year; 2 cards signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1930 Nov 5; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1928-1938; 30 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1929-1938; 9 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
        [in part, photocopies and some incomplete]
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1927-1934; no date; 3 autograph postcards signed (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1944 Oct 3; 1 telegram (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
        See also: from Loos, to family
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1928 no month no day; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      - Loos, Fritz [uncle], 1929 Mar 17; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Gerda [sister-in-law], 1946 Nov 26; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Hans [brother], 1928-1929; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Hans [brother], 1935 Nov 28; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 6)
        [incomplete; last pages wanting?]
      - Loos, Hans [brother], 1946-1947; no date; 5 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Kurt [brother], 1932 Feb 15; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Luise [sister], 1946 Sep 10; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - From Loos, to family, I.A.2
      - Loos, Anneliese, 1947 Jul 21; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1934; [1934?]; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
        [incomplete; first pages wanting?]
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1944 Mar 23; 1 telegram (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - From Hans Loos, to family, I.A.3
      - Loos, Armin [father], 1938 Feb 18; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Loos, Elizabeth (Bloomberg) [wife], 1971 Aug 26; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Loos, Kurt, 1933 Nov 24; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Between Armin and Elizabeth Loos, I.B
    - From Elizabeth, to Armin, I.B.1
      - 1941 Apr 14, 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 8)
        See also: Poetry, 1941 Apr 16
    - From Armin, to Elizabeth, I.B.2
      - Excerpts from approximately 60 letters, 1932-[1938 or 1939?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
        [photocopies]
      - 1941 May 15, 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, I.C
    - From individuals, to Loos, I.C.1
      - [Br-?, Leut.?], [1928 Jan 19?]; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - B-?, Ruth, 1926-1929; no year Nov 30; no date; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Smith, Sylvia [formerly Sylvia R.?], 1967-1968; no date; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Schubert, Richard, 1947 Feb 8; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - [Spies?], Vera [Mrs. Otto?], 1926 Mar 4; no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - From Loos, to individuals, etc., I.C.2
      - Buol, Ruth, [1950's]; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - L-?, 1925-1929; 3 autograph letters (Box 1, Folder 10)
        [last letter incomplete]
      - Sam Goody, Inc. [the day Armin died], 1971 Mar 23; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - [Spies?], Otto. sketch., 1928 Dec 19; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Friend, 1925 Apr 6; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Friend, 1926 Jun no date; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Friend, 1926 Nov 10; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Unidentifiable, no date; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Concerning musical works, I.D
    - To Loos, I.D.1
      - American Composerts Alliance
        See: Copland, Aaron.
      - Barbirolli, Sir John, 1899- [Philharmonic-Symphony Society of New York], 1941 Feb 24; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See also: From Loos, to Woolford, [John]
      - Boston Symphony Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See: Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951.
      - Chicago Symphony Orchestra, American Composer's Contest [mimeograph], 1941 Jan 30; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See also: From to Loos, to Voegeli, Henry E.
      - Copland, Aaron, 1900-, 1939 Jul 14; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970 [Yale University. School of Music, Dean], 1941 May 13; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Harris, Roy, 1898-, 1938; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        includes program
      - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951., 1931 Jan 12; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Music Mountain, 1963 Aug 10; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - National Association for American Composers and Conductors, 1963-1966; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Petri, Egon, 1881-1962., 1936 Mar 18; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See also: From Loos, to individuals.
      - Petri, [Mrs. Egon], 1940 May 5; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Rossi, Urico. (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See: Music Mountain; To Elizabeth Loos concerning Armin's music.
      - Society for the Publication of American Music, 1935-1936; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977., 1932 Sep 30; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Stokowski, Olga Samaroff, 1882-1948., 1937 Feb 2; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Symphony Society of Greater Hartford. (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See: Winograd, Arthur.
      - United States Works Progress Administration. Federal Music Project. (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Choral Contest Committee [photocopy], 1938; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Composer's Forum-Laboratory [photocopy], 1937; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - United Temple Chorus, Ernest Bloch Award Committee [mimeograph], 1964 Feb 21; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962 [signed by A.A. Baldwin, secretary], 1933 Jan. 4; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Westminster Choir School. (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
        See: Harris, Roy, 1898-
      - Winograd, Arthur [Symphony Society of Greater Hartford, Music Director], 1970 Jun 10; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Wolfson, Arthur [Congregation Emanu-El of the City of New York, Cantor], 1963 Nov 5; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Yaddo, 1941 Jun 2; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - From Loos, to individuals, I.D.2
      - B-?, Miss [Schönberg's class], no date; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 12)
        sketch with unidentified sketch of "Roman" on back [incomplete]
      - Charles H. Ditson and Company names and addresses of 15 other publishers included [carbon], 1930 Jan 22; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Crumm, Harry B. [WABC], [1938?]; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
        sketch
      - Petri, Egon, 1881-1962., 1936 Mar 8; no date; 3 autograph letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
        sketches [incomplete]
        See also: Correspondence concerning musical works; Poetry by Loos, 1936 Mar 8, original on back.
      - Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977., no date; 2 autograph letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
        See also: Correspondence concerning musical works.
      - Voegeli, Henry E. [Chicago Symphony Orchestra, manager], 1941 Mar 8; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
        See also: Chicago Symphony Orchestra, American Composer's Contest.
      - Woolford, [John, Secretary to Sir John Barbirolli], 1940 Sep 14; 1 autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 12)
        See also: correspondence concerning musical works, to Loos from Barbirolli, Sir John, 1899-
  - Business, financial, legal, to Loos, I.E
    - Board of Trade for German-American Commerce, Inc., 1934 Feb 9; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Davidsen, 1934 Feb 27; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dietrich, Dr. Herbert, 1947-1949; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dietrich, Dr. Herbert [includes 1 carbon copy], 1947 Jul 6; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dresdner Bank, 1924 Jun 30; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - German Book Importing Company, 1928 Feb 28; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - German Book Importing Company, 1928 Jan 24; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ica, Aktiengesellschaft [joint stock company], 1925 Aug 26; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - International Germanic Company Ltd., 1928 Jan 13; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
      music notes on back
    - Oscar Heilmann, 1924 May 30; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Schulte, Dr. Fritz, 1928; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified, 1927 Sep 29; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
      re: foreign loan
    - U.S. Selective Service System. Connecticut [Local Board No. 6A, Hartford County], 1942 Jul 7; 1 Typed postcard (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - To Elizabeth Loos, I.F
    - Concerning Loos's music, I.F.1
      - David, Dr. Avram [photocopy], 1975 Jun 8; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Girard, Kenneth [photocop], 1979 Oct 2; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916- [photocopy], 1974? Mar 19; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - New Britain Symphony and Concert Association [photocopy], 1972 Apr 23; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Rodriguez, Santiago [photocopy], 1975 Jun 23; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Rossi, Urico [Berkshire Quartet, violin] [photocopy], no date; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
        See also: Correspondence concerning musical works, Music Mountain.
      - Yale University Music Library [photocopy], 1975 Apr 22; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Zinn, William [New Britain Symphony Orchestra, concertmaster] [photocopy], 1973 Oct 31; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Other, I.F.2
      - Troy, Robert F. [University of Connecticut Health Center, Department of Anatomy], 1971 Mar 29; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - To individuals concerning Loos's music, I.G
    - Boelke-Bomart, Inc. and Mobart Music Publications, [Dr. Jacques-Louis Monod, Vice President], to "Whom it may concern" [photocopy], 1978 Jun 21; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Connecticut. Commission on the Arts. [Anthony S. Keller, Executive Director], to Mr. Charles Boos, [New Britain Symphony Society, President] [photocopy], 1972 Mar no date; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Girard, Kenneth, 1979 Oct 12; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 15)
      See also: To Elizabeth Loos concerning Loos's music.
    - New Britain Symphony Orchestra [Jerome Laszloffy, conductor and musical director, to Anthony S. Keller [photocopy, signed], 1971 Dec 9; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Rodriguez, Santiago, to William L. Carnow [Greater New Britain Symphony Society, treasurer] [photocopy], 1975 Jun 12; 1 autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sarch, Kenneth and Liora, to Anthony S. Keller [photocopy], 1971 Dec no date; 1 typed letter (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Zimmerman, Phil [Greater New Britain Symphony Society, President], to the Board Members [photocopy], 1974 Apr 18; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Zinn, William, to William L. Carnow [Armin Loos Memorial Fund of the Greater New Britain Symphony Society, Administrator] [photocopy], 1975 Jul 26; 1 typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
      See also: Biographical and Analytical Notes.
- Programs and program notes, 1958-1979; Series II
  Divided into three subseries. Those written by Loos are listed chronologically. Programs of performances of Loos's music are listed alphabetically by title, then alphabetically by performer.
  - Written by Loos, II.A
    - New Britain Symphony Orchestra, 1964-1971; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
      [holograph]
      5 leaves [for program 1964 May 13]
    - notes for his Symphony for String Orchestra [dedicated to Busoni] (1940), no date; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 16)
      3p.[holograph]
  - Performances of Loos's works, II.B
    - Aquarius '70, 1972 Apr 16; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 16)
      New Britain Symphony Orchestra, Jerome Laszloffy, conductor [photocopy]
    - Elegy, 5 items
      - Gerald Dargis Chorale, Gerald Dargis, conductor [photocopy], 1972 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
      - Madrigal Singers, Lehman Engel, conductor. W.P.A. Federal Music Project, winning composition, 1938 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Westminster Festival Week [the 2nd program does not include Loos's Elegy] 1938 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Four Piano Pieces, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Alan and Judith Hersh [photocopy], 1972 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Kenneth Sarch and Max Lifschitz [photocopy], 1974 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Percepts, 1977 Aug 16; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Berkshire Music Center Orchestra, Gunther Schuller, conductor
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 4] String quartet no. 4, 2 items
      - Berkshire Quartet [Urico Rossi, violin.], 1975 Jul 26 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        [See also: Correspondence concerning musical works to Loos; to Elizabeth Loos]; Sound recordings [photocopy]
      - New England Chamber Players [2nd version, world premiere] [photocopy], 1974 Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Quartet, oboe, horn, bassoon and piano] Quartet in classical style for piano and winds, 2 items
      - Hartford Conservatory Faculty Chamber Concert [photocopy], 1974 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Concert of American Chamber Music. Chris Krueger, flute, Henry Tervo, oboe, Jess Gross, clarinet, Jean Moore, horn, Steve Young, bassoon, and Ellen Polansky, piano [photocopy], 1974 Sep 15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Quintet, woodwind] Woodwind quintet (1964), 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See: Above program of Quartet in classical style for piano and winds (1974 Sep 15) for same concert.
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 1] Piano sontata no. 1 (1964), 1974 Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Lillian Birnbaum [photocopy]
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 1] Sonata no. 1 for piano solo (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Lillian Birnbaum. See: Program containing Quartet in classical style for same concert. See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 3] Piano sonata no. 3 (1967), 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See: Program containing Four piano pieces (1974) for same concert. See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 1] Sonata no. 1 (1968), 1973 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Kenneth Sarch, violin and Max Lifschitz, piano [photocopy] See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 1] Sonata no. 1 for violin and piano (1968) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See: Program containing Four piano pieces (1974) for same concert.
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 1] Violin sonata no. 1 (Allegro), 1971 Sep 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Kenneth Sarch, violin, and Liora Sarch, piano [photocopy]
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 2] Sonata for violin and piano (1971), 1979 Apr 12; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Linda Quan, violin, and Janice Weber, piano [members of the Composer's Guild for Performance] See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 2] Sonata no. 2 for violin and piano (1971) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Kenneth Sarch, piano, and Max Lifschitz, piano. See: Program containing Four piano pieces (1974) for same concert.
    - Study piece for horn, 'cello, and piano, 1971 Jun 2; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Nancy Birnbaum, violoncello, Patricia Kelleher, horn, Melissa Massicotte, piano. See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Symphony, no. 1] Adagio from Symphony no. 1 (Good-bye), 1974 Mar 7; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
      New Britain Symphony Orchestra, Jerome Laszloffy, conductor [world premiere] [photocopy] See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Symphony, no. 1] Symphony for orchestra (in memoriam Ferruccio Busoni), 1976 Mar 14 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      New Britain Symphony, Jerome Laszloffy, conductor
      [world premiere]
      [card]
    - Three pieces for horn and piano, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Andrew Spearman, horn, Clinton Adams, piano.
      See: Program containing Quartet in classical style for the same concert.
  - Other, II.C
    - New Britain Symphony Orchestra 1971 May 23, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newspaper clippings, 1963-1979; Series III
  Arranged chronologically. There are three subseries which include Reviews, etc., Other, and Press releases.
  - Reviews, etc., III.A
    - clippings [photocopies], 1971; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1972; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1973; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1974; 13 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1975; 9 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1976; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - clippings [photocopies], 1979; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Other, III.B
    - "Bloomberg's Curtain Shop to Vacate Downtown Scene," New Britain Herald, 1963 Feb 8; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
      [photocopy]
  - Press release, III.C
    - Metcalfe, Catherine [Program Assistant, Connecticut Commission in the Arts], 1972 Mar 1; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Biographical and analytical notes, 1973-1975; Series IV
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - "Armin Loos Collection", 1975 Dec 15; American Music Center; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)